Are You Done Insulting Me?
Prev  |   |  Next

Are You Done Insulting Me?

Are you Done - Part 2

The next day, I approached Taylor in one of the breaks carrying a printout of this "How to become a Hacker" essay. I was quite vexed, and wanted to consult him regarding it.

"Taylor," I said without saying hello, "what the hell does this Eric Raymond character want from me?".

"What did you find wrong with it?"

"Let's see: role playing games - you know I hate them."

"You don't need to like RPG's to be a hacker."

"Or Science Fiction. I prefer humourous writings and Realism."

"It won't make you any less of a computer geek."

"Here's another thing:", I said as I went over the document, "'Zen or Martial Arts'. You know the mere thought of hurting someone else freaks me out and that I hit like a girl.".

"Hit like a girl?", Taylor said, "Tell you what - here's my open hand. Hit it as hard as you can with your fist? Let's check your claim."

"Really," I said looking at his open hand?

"Yeah sure. I'm ready."

I backed up my right hand, and hit his fist as hard as I could. Taylor cried "ow", and rubbed his left hand with his right. Then he said out of quite a pain, "You forgot that we go to the gym twice a week."

"Oh, right… weight-training… among else. Are you alright?"

"I'll be OK.", he said as he released his left hand. "But I don't think you hit like a girl. Keep that in mind in case you get into a chick fight one day."

"Heh", I smiled, "So I'm a bit strong. So what? I still don't want to learn Martial Arts." I said. "And what kind of language is 'Python' . Who would name a language after a snake."

"Well, as far as I know Erisa, she'll probably teach you Perl instead."

"But Raymond says…"

"ESR (that's how we refer to Eric S. Raymond), is a very nice guy, but he has several faults. One of them is being a Pythoneer who bashes Perl quite irrationally. Erisa has learned Perl as the first of her so-called 'scripting languages', and she still prefers it to Python. She also told me that someone once told her that he'd rather teach people Perl at start, because it's a language they can express themselves in."

"Well, I also recall Pascal from my days,", I said, "so I guess I'll be alright."

"Jenn, " he told me as he held my hands, "I'm sure you will.".

Are you Done - Part 2

Erisa dropped by my house on Saturday. My brother answered the door, and was shocked, and a bit scared of the way she looked. After consulting me, I told him it was alright, and let her into my room.

Erisa brought the CDs of the Linux distribution (they were burned), and said I could keep them. "Before we start, let me start Windows and check for configuration and stuff," she said.

"Wow!" she said later, "65 Gigs free out of 80? You obviously don't make too much use of this machine. Well, that'll give us enough space for installing Linux."

"OK, ", she said, "now you sit at the computer and go through the installation, read the instructions and let me know what you think. I'll let you know what you should do next."

"OK, " I said, as we switched places.

Well, except for the part about re-partitioning which confused me a bit, everything was reasonably understood. Then Erisa instructed me to reboot the computer.

When it started, it displayed a nice graphical menu which said if I would like to start Linux or Windows. I chose Linux naturally. Then a large number of messages appeared (Erisa said even she didn't understand them all), and then I got the so-called "login" prompt, that asked me for a username.

"OK, " said Erisa, "we took note of your username and password, and of your root password. The root user can do anything, so it is considered a bad idea to use it all the time. When I started like you, I worked all the time as root, but you shouldn't duplicate my mistakes."

"Heh heh", I giggled. "OK, I'll just enter 'jennray' here, and 'schrodinger6590' here. OK?

"Yes."

After that, this thing called KDE loaded ("KDE is the number one desktop for chicks"), displaying a nice bootscreen. And afterwards, I saw the work screen.

"Wow!" I said, "this is beautiful.". And indeed it was: the icons were smooth and attractive, the windows had very nice decorations, it just invited people to play with it. I figured out the menu with the star was equivalent to Windows "Start" thingy, and started browsing the menus and starting applications.

"Hold it right there, girlfriend!" Erisa barfed at me, "You ain't paying me to play with Linux on my time. Now let me show you a couple of things…"

She showed me how to access the two control centers. (one for the desktop, and one for the entire system.) How to browse and manage files using the file-manager. (it had a cute Home icon), and explained about the kate text editor and why text editors in general are useful in UNIX. ("Linux belongs to a large family of operating systems, past and present, called UNIXes, which share a lot in common. So if you hear the term 'UNIX', don't freak out.")

She ended up with searching Google and the Web for some good resources for editing HTML. She bookmarked all of them in the web browser, and then said:

"Now, your homework for the next week is to prepare a homepage for yourself, after you've read everything I bookmarked you. (Possibly , along with reading it). Because you're such an uninteresting girl, you'll probably want to fill it with things you like, useless links, and raves about the Power Puff Girls. But I won't judge you. Just make sure it has a lot of content in it."

"Are you done insulting me?" I answered.

"For now", and she grinned, "see you next weekend."

"Bye, I said! " and I paid her for her time.

She sure seemed to know her stuff, but had a strange way of conveying it to me.

Prev  |   |  Next
The Human Hacking Field Guide  | Home |  I'm just a Geek…

God Works in Mysterious Ways
Prev  |   |  Next

God Works in Mysterious Ways

Taylor, Eve, Jonathan and I gathered at the living room in my house, together with our college acceptance letters, and each having his university acceptance summary. We had previously decided that we will go to the same university together, and we needed to find the most suitable one to which we were all accepted.

"OK, before we start - let me make one thing clear: I absolutely refuse to study in the East Coast." Eve said.

"Why? " I asked.

"Well, my parents moved there once when I was in the 5th grade. To Boston. I completely hated the cold, the rain, the snow, getting wet. I guess I'm a California girl."

"Very well. So we're going to pick a college in California. All for one and one for all." Taylor said, and kissed Eve on the lips.

"Besides - I did not get into M.I.T. and I guess no-one here did either." she added.

"Ahem." I said.

"Yes, Jenn?" she said as she looked at me.

"I got into M.I.T.."

"Well, I'll be damned. I guess the interviewer was flabbergasted by my then Purple hair. " Eve said, "Oh well, California colleges. I got into Berkeley! Everybody else did?".

"I got into Berkeley, too." Taylor said.

"Ahem." I said, "I was rejected from U.C. Berkeley."

"You were?" Eve said, "God Works in Mysterious Ways."

Taylor sighed, "Guess we're not going to Berkeley. All for one and one for all. How about UCLA?"

"Well, while we're setting our preferences" I said, "I'd rather not study somewhere close. I'd like to be a bit away from my parents."

"No problem. " Jonathan said, "We'll be together away from our parents." and he kissed me on the lips. "OK, ", he added, "I've got San-Diego University, University of Sacramento… hey, I got into Stanford!"

"Me too", Eve said.

"Likewise", Taylor added.

I checked my notes, "I got into Stanford, too. That's great - we're all going to Stanford."

"All for one and all in Stanford.", Eve said. There was a long period when we were just digesting the news, and just being plain joyful about it. After a while Eve said: "OK, we said we'll all major in Computer Engineering, but have different minors. My minor is going to be Linguistics. Since I already know English, Hebrew and Spanish, I might as well get the hang of other languages."

"I'm going to minor in Ancient History and Languages of the Near East." Taylor said, "I'd like to learn more about Eve's background."

Eve smiled. Jonathan said, "I think I'll be a philosophy minor. I think I'm a philosopher at heart. At least during the times I'm not an Electrician by heart."

"Well, as for me, I'm going to minor in fine arts." I said. "Maybe I have a hidden talent for painting or something like that, and if not, at least I'll find out."

"Very well, so, we're all sending the acceptance letters to Stanford, each with his selected Minor." Taylor said. "OK, now, if you'll excuse me, I think we still have some homework to do… high school one."

Prev  |   |  Next
"Who will Take a Second Look at it, unless…"  | Home |  I can write my own replacement for 'In Search of Lost Time'

Hardware Hackers are…
Prev  |   |  Next

Hardware Hackers are…

I decided to attend these LUG meetings, from then on. So on the next Wednesday, Taylor and I took the bus to the local university, and went into the room. Immediately after we entered, some guy wearing a T-shirt with a Penguin on it and some shorts said, "Hey Taylor" and as we got closer he said, "Who's the fox?"

I blushed, and then reached my hand and said "Jennifer Raymond". He shook my hand and said "Jeff Burtkowsky."

"Are you new here?" Jeff asked.

"Yes, I said. I'm Taylor's friend and Erisa's pupil."

"Nice. Erisa is a first-class hacker (whatever her other faults are). Just note that you shouldn't be offended if some guys here hit on you. Most of them are heterosexual and most of the viable girls in this club are already taken."

"That's quite alright. I'm used to guys hitting on me. I guess Linux guys are not different. But I have a very sweet and caring boyfriend, so I kindly interrupt these passes."

"What does he do?"

"He's in high school too. Heavily into Electronics."

"Electronics? Wow, that's impressive. Hardware hackers are a whole class above software hackers. I mean we software hackers write code, and it can run everywhere there's a gcc-backend on. It just works, and if it doesn't, it is almost certainly the fault of what's above the hardware. Hardware hackers… now they deal with the physical world, where one wrong wiring can make a world of damage. Now, if we are cool, they are above-cool."

"What's 'gcc' and what are its backends?."

"Well," Taylor interrupted, "gcc is a compiler that is not very fast, does not produce spectacular code, but is one of the seven wonders of the modern world."

"How's that?" I asked.

"Well, it can run everywhere and compile code for almost every architecture and has tons of useful extensions, and can compile many languages, and can cross-compile and it's open-source. The Linux Kernel, for example, can only be compiled using gcc."

"I understand you're not a programmer," Jeff said.

"Well, I studied Pascal for two years in high school. Could not get myself to really become enthusiastic about it. And I had better things to learn at school."

"Well, Pascal is a sexless language, if you ask me. And, plus, I think programming is not something you can be taught in school. Some people are better programmers after 1 year, than many are with 10 years of experience. It vastly depends on your attitude."

"Hmmmm….", I answered, "I confess that the only reason I want to become a hacker now, is because I want to have something good to show off to get to a good college. But I admit that creating a homepage for myself turned out to be fun."

"In that case, you might grow to like hacking. If you don't - I suggest you find something else to do, that you happen to like. People who are not enthusiastic about their work, are almost never good hackers."

It made me a bit worried, so I just said "Yes, naturally.".

At that moment, Erisa entered the room. She looked around, and eventually fixed her gaze upon me. "Jenn, you came!". (Could you believe it - she called me "Jenn"!). "Yep, " I told her, "I had a very nice conversation with Taylor and Jeff over here."

"Hi guys!" Erisa said, as she approached us.

"Jenn here is quite clueless about Linux, but she is actually quite persistent, so she may become a really leet haxor, sooner or later."

I did not understand what a "leet haxor" is, but I figured it was probably something good. The other guys laughed.

The presentation was way over my head, but Taylor, whom I sat next to, was kind enough to explain some things. I eventually understood or thought I understood most of what was going on there.

At the break, I noticed that some other guy was typing enthusiastically on his laptop's keyboard and constantly using the mouse. I approached him. I saw a huge black window saying "XChat" in the title bar, and lots of weird text looking like a conversation.

"Are you talking with someone?" I asked him.

"As a matter of fact, yes. It's called IRC - Internet Relay Chat. It's actually quite useful for resolving random problems, but it can also become very addictive."

"Can you show me how to use it?"

"I guess."

Apparently you connect to a server, and then join various "channels", where "channel" is a fancy name for a chat-room, where you talk by entering text in a small text entry. You can also initiate a private conversation and do other stuff. I found the idea intriguing.

"And the people you talk to, can be from the other side of the world. " He said. "And I recommend Freenode for most purposes. It's a really nice network. Here, let me E-mail it to you.

Taylor, Erisa and I took the bus home. On the way, Taylor and Erisa spent their time talking about computers and computing news, while I was too afraid to interrupt their conversation and ask what they were talking about.

Prev  |   |  Next
I'm just a Geek…  | Home |  BETH!

MIME, POE, XUL and other Beasts
Prev  |   |  Next

MIME, POE, XUL and other Beasts

I continued to learn new things everyday. With the help of Erisa, I learned about C, (which is much sexier than Pascal), Internet Network programming, writing web applications, some GUI programming (very hard to get exactly right, but still fun), working with databases, and more. Erisa gave me problems like "fix at least three of the bugs in the bug-tracker of project foo", or "add a new feature to project bar".

One thing I discovered was that reading code and understanding it was difficult. Much more than writing it. But after I understood how it worked, I could implement the fix or the new feature reasonably easily.

The IRC was also a great help. Whenver I encountered a problem, I could join the appropriate IRC channel, and ask about it. If that did not work, I usually tried searching the web, or posting to the local Linux User Group's mailing list, or to web-forums. IRC was a very nice experience: I met many people from all over the world, and chatted with them endlessly. Many of the chats were fun, but quite redundant, but a lot of them provided new insights or gave me useful new knowledge. There was only one thing that bothered me.

When working on my homepage, I could very easily express myself. I was able to put pictures, sounds, hyperlinks, styled text, and files there. This was much more difficult in the IRC that was text only, with a few pretty useless embellishments, URLs that had to be copy and pasted, and all kind of other limitations. I wanted more.

In one of the LUG meetings, Jeff, some other guy called Ervin, and I chatted between ourselves before the presentation, and somehow we ended up discussing the IRC. So I brought this along.

"So, maybe, " said Jeff, "we need to create a new IRC protocol, that will allow such media. God knows I heard some people say they also want to be able to use Mathematical notation. Ever been to a Maths channel before? The expressions there are not a pretty sight."

Ervin and I laughed, and Jeff joined us.

"So we need a new protocol? What are we going to base it on?" I asked.

"Well, on MIME probably.", Jeff said. MIME is a standard for sending and receiving data and sub-data, identifying its type, etc.

"Tell you what?" he said, "we can write a prototype for a server in Perl or Python using POE or Twisted." I was surprised to realise that I knew what it meant.

"Yeah, " I said, "and let's write the client in Mozilla's XUL. That will give us all the media handling for free."

"Nice thinking, Jenn, " Jeff said, and we gave each other a high five.

"But then we have lots of potential security issues, which we would like to avoid, and we need to think of a robust protocol." I added.

"So let's go to the black-board and start designing everything." Jeff said.

We scribbled a lot of boxes, arrows, buzzwords, state machines and all other kinds of things. It was Erisa's turn to give a presentation and when she saw everybody next to the blackboard, being involved in the design, she was immediately puzzled.

"What are you doing?" she asked.

"Hi Erisa! We're designing the next generation IRC protocol, with many improvements over vanilla IRC."

"Yeah, like Media support, styles, Maths, a more robust and powerful protocol and more features, etc. It was Jenn's idea."

"Interesting", Erisa said, "since you all seem to be so much involved in it, I say that we delay my presentation in an hour. Jenn, I'm running out of things I really need to teach you, and you may wish to embark on this project, just to try and get closer to a demi-god status for yourself."

I blushed. "Sure, Erisa. It sounds very exciting. I don't know how good a coder I am. Can anyone here become my partner for pair programming?"

Lots of people volunteered. "Jeff,", I addressed him, "Will you be my partner?" I felt I could trust him.

"Sure, why not. If only to make my girlfriend jealous. OK, Jenn and I will write a spec [= specification] together and send it to you. Jenn do you know DocBook?"

"Heard about it, but no."

"Then I guess I'll have to teach it to you. It's not that hard."

"Cool. ", I said, "Now back to designing this baby…"

Prev  |   |  Next
"She still is…"  | Home |  "That would be as Evil as HTML E-mail is…"

Most of our Electrical Engineering graduates cannot…
Prev  |   |

Most of our Electrical Engineering graduates cannot…

Hexadecimal Dollar

"Man, this is so exciting" Eve said as the four of us were entering the hall in which the beginning ceremony of the new Stanford scholastic year for Computer Science students took place.

"I mean", she continued, "come on, this is Stanford. Tons of great names, lots of other departments, lots of interesting classes we could take, many extra-curricular activities."

"And we're in the middle of Silicon Valley - we can attend conferences of all these companies, big and small; we can visit IBM or Google…"

"And we're studying Comp. Eng.. One day we'll be more than just creators of bit buckets, but people who can actually wire transistors and stuff like that."

"Of course, once we start having homework and we're going to have bad teachers, we'll curse this place to death, and continually bitch about it, but right now - I'm so excited."

"And the best thing about it", she said as she started kissing Taylor, "is that I'm doing it with my best friends."

"I hope I'm more than just your friend." Taylor said. "Oh you are" she replied and they started seriously making out.

"I could not help overhearing what you were saying", said a man in his fifties or sixties who approached Jonathan and me. "For your information, most of our Electrical Engineering Graduates, cannot even replace a light bulb."

"Hmmm… makes sense.", Jonathan said.

"Yes, they are practically specialised mathematicians."

"What's up with them?" He asked, pointing at Taylor and Eve.

"Well," I said, "it's a combination of raging hormones and what we really hope is a match made in heaven."

"Wait a sec… we haven't introduced ourselves! I'm Jennifer Raymond and this is my boyfriend Jonathan Demarco."

"Nice to meet you. I'm Professor Emeritus Don Knuth [Kanooth]."

"Knuth," Eve said as she let herself out of Taylor, "What about Knuth?"

"Nice to meet you Miss, I'm Don Knuth." said the professor as he extended his hand.

"Oh my god," Eve got excited as she shook his hand, "Don Knuth, the TeX [Tekh] guy."

Knuth nodded an said, "Yes, TeX".

"Hi!", Eve continued, "I'm a… I'm a great, I'm a great adm… ehhhh…," and she fainted into Taylor's arms.

Hexadecimal Dollar

We were in a relatively quiet side room. Prof. Knuth was there and also the four of us, (with Eve still unconscious) and a doctor. Eventually, Eve woke up.

"Oh my God," she said, "…Taylor, Jennifer, Jonathan…" she looked around.

"Professor Knuth! Oh I'm so sorry."

"Nah! That's OK.", he said.

"Ah, OK. Just understand that meeting you is sort of like meeting God."

"I'm not God. " he said, "Hell, last time I tried, it took me two days to build the Roman Empire." Some people laughed or giggled. "Here, ", he continued. "I made something for you." and he gave her a check.

"2.56 dollars," she turned the check, "To my great adm." she said, "Wow! One Knuthian Hexadecimal Dollar just for me."

"Are you going to cash it in?" Jonathan asked whimsically.

"Are you kidding? This stuff sells on eBay for at least a hundred bucks…"

I burst into laughter.

"I'm just kidding", Eve said, "I'm going to cherish it.".

I admit that I did not entirely understand everything that happened right away. But when I returned to my dorm room, I spent some time browsing the web looking for answers. I still have a lot to learn, but I'm getting there. I guess I'm just a geek who's trying to make the world a better place.

Prev  |   |
I can write my own replacement for 'In Search of Lost Time'  | Home |

"Raesha - meh ho owmer?"
Prev  |   |  Next

"Raesha - meh ho owmer?"

Eve dropped by the computer lab some time later. "Listen, my extended family is holding a Passover Seder at our house next Saturday's night. Normally, what I would have done then, is go out of the house to avoid it. But this year, I decided to stay."

"OK, " I said, "So?"

"Well, I was wondering if you'd like to join us?"

"Sure, " I said, "I've got nothing better to do at that time."

"Great." Eve said. "I'll see you then."

So the next Saturday, I took some time to prepare. I recalled that some observant Jews frowned upon females wearing pants and stuff like that, so I wore a nice dress. And so I walked to Eve's house.

Eve answered the door. "Hi Jennifer!" she said. She was also wearing a nice dress with flowers and all. There was a lot of commotion in the house, and many voices, both of grown-ups and children were heard. "Please come in, make yourself at home. Here, let me introduce you to my family."

And so, I met with Eve's uncles, aunts, cousins, and grand-parents. After we finished meeting all of them we went to the living room, where Daniel and his cousin Deborah were busy playing a video game. "You suck at this. " Daniel announced, as he won another round.

"Well, you have this game at your house, while I don't, so you can get much more practice." his cousin responded.

"Would you two like a round?" Daniel asked Eve and I, "this game is stupid anyhow."

"OK.", "Sure." we said.

Deborah looked a bit at us as she released her game-pad. "Say, you two have such wonderful hair. Can I play with it?"

"Hey, I want to play with it, too!" Daniel said.

"Sure!" I said as I grabbed the game-pad.

"No problem here, either. Just don't… don't mix the strands of two different people." Eve said.

"Here, we'll sit apart." I said as I took a little distance from Eve.

"So what does every button do?" I said.

Eve explained as best as she could, and we started to play. I was not particularly good at it, but Eve seemed to suck even more.

"Daniel's right. This game is stupid." she said. "You know, some of the old DOS games were much more intelligent. Lots of puzzle games, Adventure games, and things you need to think to progress in. I still like to play them using a Linux-based DOS emulator."

"Well, I've never been a big computer games fan. " I said, "Freecell is almost the only game I play. Of course, I find playing it with PySol on Linux much nicer than with the Windows-shipped one."

"Heh. Microsoft Freecell is absolute crap." she said, as her character successfully hit mine.

She added: "You know, I actually read a review for a recent game that came out - a first-person shoot-them-up. The review said it had good graphics and all, but otherwise you had an infinite amount of ammunition, and you just had to kill an infinite amount of monsters coming at you. Pretty dull. Still it concluded by saying it may be good for the hot summer, instead of saying it sucked completely."

"You're doing it all wrong! " Deborah said to Daniel, "Here let me show you how to arrange a girl's hair."

"Heh. " I said, and we continued playing for a several minutes.

"Everybody, we're getting started!" Eve's mother cried, and we gathered to the dining table. Eve and I rose up, and walked towards the table. As we passed by, Mrs. Siegel said, "Eve, Jennifer, what happened to your hair?"

Eve and I looked at each other, then burst out laughing simultaneously. "Heh, never mind." Eve said, "we'll fix it later."

Eve and a few other relatives who knew how to read Hebrew, started reading the Passover Hagaddah (= Ceremonial Transcript) in turn, translating it to English on the fly, each time instructing us what to do. When we reached the part with the four sons that the Jewish Law spoke against, and the Evil one, Eve said:

"For this part, I have prepared in advance a Goyah…" and she pointed at me.

"Heh, a Shiksa."

"OK, I'll read it with your help." I said.

"OK: 'Rasha - mah hu omer?'"

"Raesha - meh ho owmer?"

"Close enough!", and so we continued.

After a while the food came, and after a meal some people continued reading the Hagaddah, while most of the others packed everything or simply talked or played around. It was a lot of fun.

After the ceremony, Eve and I fixed the strands of each other's hair. "You know, Daniel and Deb may have a hidden talent as hair stylists." Eve said.

"You think so?" I said, as we switched places, "Your hair is a bit inconsistent. If they do have a talent, then I guess it is indeed very well hidden."

Prev  |   |  Next
Man, it was so exciting!  | Home |  "Abandoning" Debian

I can write my own replacement for 'In Search of Lost Time'
Prev  |   |  Next

I can write my own replacement for 'In Search of Lost Time'

After the summer vacation arrived, and we had some time before our Sophomore year at the university, Eve said that she'd rather not work this year, and instead have a lot of "clean fun with my friends.". We decided to restrict ourselves to California and vicinity in our touring.

Using our car, we drove everywhere. We went everywhere we could think of. We hiked in Yosemite, been to Disneyland, visited the San-Diego Zoo. We went to a lot of Linux-related conferences that took place in the summer, and met a great deal of fellow enthusiasts. Eve decided we should take the tour through Berkeley University, and after the tour, she went to see the rooms where BSD (= an early and pioneering version of UNIX) was developed, and where the GIMP (an image manipulation program) was developed. I think it was her idea of heaven.

When Eve wasn't driving, she spent a lot of time writing things on her PDA. She said she worked on a lot of articles, and Wikipedia entries. Eventually, at the first Saturday before the last, we took a quiet day and went to a beach north of Los-Angeles. As the boys went swimming again, Amanda, Eve and I sat on some chairs on the seashore. Eve sat on her chair wearing her bikini, I sat next to her with a shirt over my bathing suit, and Amanda sat beside me with Eve's laptop. The laptop had speakers connected to it which we used to play music.

We were finishing to hear an interesting punk song that Eve was fond of, and has sort of grown on Amanda and me. In fact, it was Amanda who picked it up this time. After the song ended, Eve said:

"Yeah, Baby, yeah! I really like the guitar-and-drums solos in this song. This guy has an excellent voice. His technique is usually not too good but here he does pretty well."

Amanda said: "Eve, are you sure you shouldn't become a music critique?"

"Nah", Eve said, "I'm a woman of many talents, but I need to work at what I'm likely to earn some money from."

Amanda giggled, "OK. OK.". "So what song would you like to hear next?" she asked.

"I'd like to hear 'I'm not a Girl, not yet a Woman' by Britney Spears", Eve said.

"Britney Spears? I thought you hated her." I said.

"Yeah", Amanda said, "I'm surprised you even have this song on your laptop."

"Oh, give the poor girl a break. Some of her songs are pretty decent." Eve said to us.

"One Britney coming up." Amanda said.

"You know, " Eve said, "I think I'd like to be an Objectivist-slash-Libertarian. I mean, they rebel against the system, which works for me. But they are also pro-Capitalistic and everything, as long as it's uncontrolled Capitalism, which is also something the new and improved me, really believes in, instead of the 'Anti-Big-Business' crap."

"Eve," I said, "you'll be a wonderful Objectivist-slash-Libertarian."

"Yep.", she said, "Man, I'm going to miss my punky anti-Capitalistic self…"

"No feelings of yearning here." Amanda said.

"None here either." I added.

Eve said, "Hmmm… you're right, there's nothing to miss really. Man, to think of how I wasted all this time being what I was. I can write my own replacement for 'In Search of Lost Time', and publish it, and it would be better than the original, and I will win the Pulitzer Prize for it and be on shows like Oprah…"

I stopped reading my book and placed it on my lap. Then I said: "Oh Eve, come on, look at you! You're a beautiful person: you're smart, cool, talented, likable, … you look great…" Eve smiled, "and you're my best female friend and you're dating my best male friend."

"I'm sorry, but I don't think you've wasted any time."

Eve rose up, and I quickly followed her. She approached me and before I knew it, she hugged me and I hugged her back. "I love you.", she said. "I love you, too.", I said to her. We remained hugging each other for some time and then went back to our seats.

Then the guys returned. "Hey did we miss anything?" Taylor said.

"Yep, " Eve said as she rose and tied her hands around his neck. "I am a beautiful person…"

"I can see that", Taylor said.

"…and Jennifer and I love each other dearly. We're seriously considering dumping you guys, living together, eloping, et cetera".

"But luckily for you, we may wish to have some babies, so…"

You can always count on Eve to convey the serious things in a completely non-serious way…

Prev  |   |  Next
God Works in Mysterious Ways  | Home |  Most of our Electrical Engineering graduates cannot…

The Human Hacking Field Guide
  |   |  Next

The Human Hacking Field Guide

Shlomi Fish

                        <shlomif@shlomifish.org>

Copyright © 2004 Shlomi Fish

This document is copyrighted by Shlomi Fish under the Creative Commons Attribution Share-Alike License version 2.0 (or at your option a greater version).

Revision History
Revision 1134 | 2004-08-20 | shlomif
Started working on this document after forking the template of an older one.
Revision 1143 | 2004-08-21 | shlomif
Added up to the middle of the "Are you done insulting me?" chapter.
Revision 1152 | 2004-08-22 | shlomif
Added to the end of "I'm just a geek".
Revision 1158 | 2004-08-22 | shlomif
Added to the end of the first IRC conversation ("BETH!").
Revision 1168 | 2004-08-24 | shlomif
Added to the end of "She still is…"
Revision 1168 | 2004-08-27 | shlomif
Added to the end of "Evil HTML E-mail"
Revision 1194 | 2004-08-27 | shlomif
Added to the end of "TRIZ"
Revision 1203 | 2004-08-30 | shlomif
Added to the end of "Divine's Good"
Revision 1266 | 2004-09-30 | shlomif
Added to the end of "'Abandoning' Debian" and fixed many typos and incorrections.
Revision 1280 | 2004-10-02 | shlomif
Fixed many typos, many of which were discovered by Andrew Dexter.
Revision 1284 | 2004-10-05 | shlomif
Added to the End of "RMS is Coming to Town".
Revision 1287 | 2004-10-07 | shlomif
Added to the End of "God Works in Mysterious Ways".
Revision 1289 | 2004-10-09 | shlomif
Fixed many typos reported by Uri Bruck.
Revision 1369 | 2005-05-20 | shlomif
Fixed some typos.
Revision 1373 | 2005-05-27 | shlomif
Finished the document, and spell-checked it.
Revision 1379 | 2005-05-28 | shlomif
Changed "FreeNode" to "Freenode". Also fixed two minor but important typos and mis-punctuations.
Revision 1380 | 2005-05-28 | shlomif
Fixed some missing quotes, courtesy of Freenode's AthlonRob.
Revision 1382 | 2005-05-28 | shlomif
Read the story cover to cover, and fixed many typos I discovered.
Revision 1384 | 2005-05-30 | shlomif
Fixed some problems courtesy of Steve Harris.
Revision 1389 | 2005-06-01 | shlomif
Added another joke to the last chapter.
Revision 1414 | 2005-10-14 | shlomif
Revamped a part in "Divine's Good". Also fixed a lot of other bad phrasing, punctuation, etc.
Revision 1418 | 2005-10-17 | shlomif
Made the "radius" detail much more realistic. (10 km instead of 40 km)
Revision 1443 | 2005-11-05 | shlomif
Fixed the major/minor mix-ups in "God Works in Mysterious Ways".
Revision 1443 | 2005-11-05 | shlomif
Corrected a typo.
Revision 1559 | 2005-11-05 | shlomif
Corrected a typo and changed a word to a variant with more character.
Revision 1685 | 2007-04-09 | shlomif
Corrected a few errors in "Search of Lost Time"
Revision 1752 | 2007-05-09 | shlomif
Revamped the beginning (discussion of how to get into a better college) to make it more believable.
Revision 1841 | 2008-07-15 | shlomif
Revamped the start of the beach scene.
Revision 2710 | 2009-09-07 | shlomif
Revamped the "Committing Adultery in Your Heart is…" part, a little.
Revision 2768 | 2009-09-14 | shlomif
Made various corrections and enhancements.
Revision 3001 | 2009-10-06 | shlomif
Some grammar, and formatting corrections. Changed dot-dot-dots to Unicode ellipses ("…"). Converted a quote to a blockquote.
Revision 3135 | 2009-11-06 | shlomif
Converted the spelling of "Maths" to the commonwealth spelling (which is the standard spelling used for my English stories).

Table of Contents

The Things you do to Get to University
Are You Done Insulting Me?

Are you Done - Part 2

I'm just a Geek…
Hardware Hackers are…
BETH!
"She still is…"
MIME, POE, XUL and other Beasts
"That would be as Evil as HTML E-mail is…"
TRIZ
"Divine"'s Good
Committing Adultery in Your Heart is…
Man, it was so exciting!
"Raesha - meh ho owmer?"
"Abandoning" Debian
RMS is Coming to Town
"Who will Take a Second Look at it, unless…"
God Works in Mysterious Ways
I can write my own replacement for 'In Search of Lost Time'
Most of our Electrical Engineering graduates cannot…

Hexadecimal Dollar

The Things you do to Get to University

My name is Jennifer. Jennifer Susan Raymond, to be exact. I live in Los-Angeles, in one of those nice neigbourhoods that they always show in movies. I am in my high-school senior year now.

Let me tell you some things about myself. The first thing is that I'm a honour student. I especially like Maths. Its high school exercises are easy and fun and the difficult ones, which can be found in puzzle books and Maths competitions, are very challenging. I'm also good in other subjects, but Maths is really my passion. Other than that I'm blonde, have a cute face (I don't really consider myself beautiful, but guys seem to think so) and try to dress very elegantly. As a Maths geek, I sure have a social life. Everybody around me seems to like me.

Finally, I should tell about Taylor, Taylor Lawrence. He's my best friend. We became friends when we were in the fourth grade and were both grounded for 4 weeks. We instantly became friends. When we were 12 and we started having, eh, sexual sensations, we started dating each other. Then we both had a crush on different people, and we were relieved when we found out. We decided exploring our feelings would not be a worthwhile goal, and we dated other people since.

Taylor is probably even more popular than I am. Even though he wears prescription glasses, he looks great, and girls almost always agree to go with him on dates. (And sometimes ask him themselves.) One thing he seems to like and I don't is computers. He spends hours on end tampering with his computer at home. Mine, on the other hand, is almost always turned off. I have good hand writing, thank you, so I don't need a word processor. I turn it on only to listen to audio files, do some random browsing in the Internet (either for research, or to kill time or whatever) or play Freecell or Tetris. I think computers are impersonal and boring.

It all started one day when I was attending class, paying attention to the teacher, when suddenly it hit me: I don't have either any special skills and have never really been involved in the community. So, no prestigious college will prefer me over someone else. This has worried me so much that for the rest of the day, I just wrote down what the teacher said in my notebook thoughtlessly, and kept worrying about this issue.

I really want to graduate from somewhere nice where I can be proud of myself, and have the entire world at my disposal. But my entire life I've been concerned only about myself and my friends, trying to become happy, (and having a pretty good success at it), and just doing what school required me to do. I've never really been involved in anything for the community. And I never found it necessary to get any special skills, unless you call hitting the gym twice a week (with Taylor), jogging and biking special.

So I was relieved when I met Taylor that day, when we both finished school.

"Taylor, I'm worried about college." I told him.

"Why?" he said.

"I don't have any special skills and no community involvement."

"Jenn, you're sweet, intelligent and the kindest person I know. Every college will be glad to have you."

"So are most of the other candidates they get, but as opposed to me they do have some special skills and show some community involvement. How am I going to get it by the end of this year?"

"Well, you might as well try."

"Try what?"

"Learning a special skill", he said.

"A special skill? Like what?"

"You could study Sumerian!"

"Sumerian? What on Earth would I do with Sumerian?", I said, unamused.

"Talk to native speakers of Sumerian, of course."

Now I was angry. "They're all dead!"

"OK, ok. How about Latin or Hebrew or Greek?"

"I have enough problems with Spanish, thank you."

"Si, comprendo." Taylor said. "OK, OK", he continued. "I know - why don't you help the poor or whatever. Tutor kids with difficulties."

"Well…", I thought for a moment, "Taylor, you're just making up random suggestions."

Taylor thought for a moment.

"How about if you do something I can help you with and you can relate to and will also be knowledgable. Jenn, what do you say about becoming an open-source hacker?"

From talking to Taylor, I already knew that hacker did not necessarily mean a computer intruder, but rather someone who accomplished things very enthusiastically. So I told him:

"Open-source hacker? You know perfectly well that I'm a computer-phobic."

"Jennifer, you're a computer phobic now, but you can grow to like computers. I mean what are your options? Become an Electronics hacker like Jonathan is?"

Jonathan is my boyfriend, and has been since the start of the eleventh grade. He's the best boyfriend I ever had. He also likes to build machines with wires, batteries, and many other components I can't remember now. He and Taylor have become good friends.

"Electronics? You know I have two left hands, with these kind of things."

"Jenn, but you're left-handed!"

"So I have two right-hands! Taylor, are we going to argue about semantics now?"

"OK, but Jenn,", and he held my hands, "I want you to better relate to what I'm doing".

"Hmmm…." I said. I started feeling guilt and confusion and lots of other feelings. "Alright. ", I said, "I'll be an open-source hacker. Or at least try to. So… are you going to give me private lessons and stuff?"

"Sure, why not. " he said, "Wait a second! Hold that thought - I think I have a better idea. Come with me." he said, and he went down the hall.

I followed him for a few hallways and then entered with him into a computer lab. There he walked to some figure (looked like a girl) with purple (!) hair.

"Hi!" he said.

"Hiiiii…" I heard an enthusiastic female voice. "Whatcha doing here?"

"Jenn, please come here. Jenn I'd like you to meet Eve Siegel, who likes to be called 'Erisa'. Erisa, I told you about Jenn."

I looked at this Erisa character. Her hair was dyed purple, her face had too much makeup, and her facial expression was horrid. Remember that episode in "Sabrina - The Teenage Witch" where Sabrina transforms herself into a punk? She looked only a bit better than that.

"Hi" I said reluctantly.

"Hmmm… " said Erisa, "a bit too elegant for this school, aren't we. I know your type of girls. Let me guess: you are a honour student, right?"

"Yes," I told her.

"You exercise a lot".

I was becoming worried, "yeah".

"You listen to these girlie bands like NSync, All Saints, Backstreet Boys, Britney Spears and…"

"Well,", I wanted to say that I did not like NSync much.

"Yes, Atomic Kitten! These babes are the worst."

How does she know that I have all their CDs?

"Furthermore, you're a goody two shoes, never violated any rules, your parents are proud of you, you watch shows like 'Friends' and 'Seinfeld' and 'Sabrina'. Eukh… I hate Melissa Joan Hart so much…"

I could not take it anymore. She seemed to know everything about me, I started crying and left the room to the hallway. I hardly even noticed that everyone in the lab was looking at me.

Taylor went out and came to me. He hugged me and calmed me down.

"Am I as superficial as she describes?" I asked after I stopped crying.

"Jenn, don't take Erisa so seriously. She's a bit of a punk, and seem to have a grudge against the world at large and pop culture in particular."

"Why do you want her to tutor me in hacking?"

"Because she is a girl, so you won't have prejudice."

"She might be a girl, but she doesn't seem like a human being."

"Trust me, she is once you get to know her better. And she gets to know you."

"Can't you find another girl hacker to tutor me?"

"Jennifer… she's the best girl hacker in a 10-kilometre radius and one of the best hackers I know, female or male. She's the best person I can think of."

"Fine," I told him, "I'll give it a shot.". The things you do to get into university.

We entered the room again, and Taylor and I approached Erisa.

"Erisa, Jennifer here would like to become an open-source hacker."

"She?" she made a fake laugh, "what for?"

"To get into a better college.", I said.

"You want to engage in a purely altruistic activity for a selfish cause? Well, I won't be the judge of that."

"Hmmpff," I said.

"Anyway, if you want me to tutor you, it will cost you. My software is free, girlfriend, but my time isn't. 20 bucks an hour. And trust me, I'm almost never this cheap. I'm just doing it as a favour to Taylor here."

"20 dollars is fine, I guess." I told her.

She opened her bag, took out the school's students list, said "Jennifer?", (I said "Raymond"), and checked my address. "Heh", she said, "a couple of blocks from my house." She took note of my name in her PDA that lay on the computer's table.

"Now for some homework. Go to the Internet and read 'How to become a Hacker' by Eric S. Raymond. I'll drop by in two days, and guide you through the installation process of 'Mandrake Linux'. Chicks dig Mandrake, and while I'm using Debian, it'd probably be the best for you."

"Thanks, I said." I took a mental note of the resource, shook Erisa's hand, and left the lab.

  |   |  Next
  |   |  Are You Done Insulting Me?